<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Hazel&#39;s website</title>
  
  
  <link href="http://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://example.com/"/>
  <updated>2023-12-04T21:25:05.100Z</updated>
  <id>http://example.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Hazel Han</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Van Gogh Museum 3/12/23</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/12/04/Van-Gogh-Museum-3-12-23/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/12/04/Van-Gogh-Museum-3-12-23/</id>
    <published>2023-12-04T21:15:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-12-04T21:25:05.100Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>省流版：来河南旅游梵高博物馆真的值得一去！（当然我尊重不同的审美和口味（转身（没品味的东西</p><p>皮卡丘还在免费发卡的时候我轻轻观望了一下梵高，想着特展开到近二月份就没去抢票，结果貌似十月底就不发小卡了。but still，我佛系地约了当时能约的最早的周末并且规划了订阅NS周末免费卡的时间。总之拖到了昨天才终于去逛。</p><p>Anyway，没有五十欧黄牛诱惑我连皮卡丘的展品都没靠近（因为在排大队），但因为这个活动，梵高馆展厅一层特别吵。尖锐爆鸣是不太有，但所有人都在大声讲话。I really don’t get it. 一层整体给我一种很迷惑的感觉，可能宝可梦任务页里有相关任务吧，观众像游魂一样比照着自己的任务纸，让我觉得这种quest比起做成博物馆活动还是搞成城市定向比较好。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;省流版：来河南旅游梵高博物馆真的值得一去！（当然我尊重不同的审美和口味（转身（没品味的东西&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;皮卡丘还在免费发卡的时候我轻轻观望了一下梵高，想着特展开到近二月份就没去抢票，结果貌似十月底就不发小卡了。but still，我佛系地约了当时能约的最早的周末并且规划了</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Diary | My Feelings</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/04/14/Diary-My-Feelings/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/04/14/Diary-My-Feelings/</id>
    <published>2023-04-14T15:33:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-14T15:57:47.013Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It feels like that I’ve been not talking about my feelings for a long time since I no longer write down my diary. Actually I’ve been thinking about lots of things these days, like right now the sentence in my head is: so much are lost during translation. (That’s just because I’ve been watching Emily in Paris and Emily said that, no other meanings lol)</p><p>But for crying out loud, what is there to feel?</p><p>I haven’t had a serious crush on anybody, since maybe 2021, and my friends circle stays approximately the same as 2020. I hang a lot with old acquaintances, not bothering to meet anyone new. Sometimes I felt stuck here, doing something I never truly loved, yet have decided to keep doing for probably the rest of my life.</p><p>I need a change, but I know that change does not come from the environment or the stage that I am in. I can change anytime, even right now theoretically.</p><p>But I’m not sure if I still can bring about changes to myself. I used to be constantly changing, recreating myself during different life stages that I was in - in that case, it’s actually that I reinvent myself every time I enter a new school. I felt satisfied, and maybe a little sorry for my ‘past lives’ that I’ve chosen to throw away. But it turns out I’ve grown up pretty well thanks to that.</p><p>But I know that I’ve stayed the same for at least 4 years. I still haven’t out-grown that 17-year-old me. Maybe I know things better now, but I have the same fears, I don’t have many new friends, I still hate sports, I can’t decide on what I truly like, and I didn’t find love.</p><p>I used to be older than my real age, but now I feel like I’ve been left behind. This is the true sad story.</p><p>Can’t wait to really feel like a 20-year-old.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It feels like that I’ve been not talking about my feelings for a long time since I no longer write down my diary. Actually I’ve been thin</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Diary | Happy events</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/04/13/Diary-Happy-events/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/04/13/Diary-Happy-events/</id>
    <published>2023-04-13T10:12:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-13T16:26:05.738Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just ate an ice-cream and went back to dorm holding a box of chicken chips (Bing says its real name is popcorn chicken, but whatever) bought by a best friend (I wouldn’t mention her real name here for privacy reasons but, Love her!!). So I rushed to open my laptop and write these down. I mean, nothing means more to me than a treat! (God I am so vain)</p><p>Gonna write down more about today later.</p><p>It’s past midnight, AGAIN! Actually I played game on my iPad for like 4 hours before going for a shower. I hate myself. (No I don’t.)</p><p>I left half an episode of Emily in Paris unwatched, but I’m not watching that today. No I am not. I will not. I will go to bed as soon as I finish this.</p><p>So some happy events: I recieved the email from school confirming my payment - so it went well after all. Now all I have to worry about is housing (and plane tickets, and course issues, and my final thesis, and experiments, and tomorrow’s exam, but no worries)</p><p>I like spending time with a friend.</p><p>Off to bed now :)</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just ate an ice-cream and went back to dorm holding a box of chicken chips (Bing says its real name is popcorn chicken, but whatever) bou</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Diary | I am mad maybe not</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/04/12/Diary-I-am-mad-maybe-not/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/04/12/Diary-I-am-mad-maybe-not/</id>
    <published>2023-04-12T13:52:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-13T03:19:41.805Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Still working on my Data Mining midterm on Friday…</p><p>Yet there are so much things that I wanted to say. Yes, today, is some k-pop idol’s birthday (whom I hate to mention ‘cus it seems stupid to do so, and for christ’s sake I cannot even consider myself as A REAL FAN!!).</p><p>Mom and dad completed the payment to TUd which I mentioned yesterday, and now I owe them so much that I doubt I can ever pay back. Feeling crazy for not choosing the 100% fee waiver option.</p><p>Well but good things happen, too. I went to this k-pop ‘running’ event with a friend and spent a whole lot of good time there sitting on the damp grass. We were crazy, well at least I am. Singing along and screaming things out loud. And (actually I am finishing from where I left last night and it’s now 11 am) I finished reading through the slides (I mean hundreds of pages of bad English) so now midterm is no longer a problem (I guess…).</p><p>So, to wrap up, I’ve had a good time and maybe I’ve gone crazy. But whatever.</p><p>Good night and have a good day!!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Still working on my Data Mining midterm on Friday…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet there are so much things that I wanted to say. Yes, today, is some k-pop id</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Diary | The Payment</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/04/11/Diary-The-Payment/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/04/11/Diary-The-Payment/</id>
    <published>2023-04-11T09:03:49.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-13T16:28:12.974Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I guess this is it! I mean IT, my personal blog&#x2F;website.</p><p>When I was building this yesterday (constantly referring to a step-by-step blog that is), I started planning for the contents I display on these pages. I wish to record&#x2F;share (though I doubt anyone would bother reading all these) my life, my thoughts and my experience, yet in an non-personal way. I wanted to publish my diary yet at the same time preserve what little the internet has spared for my privacy.</p><p>I wanted this to be my public diary. I’ll try to nurture a habit of writing something down each day. It is interesting that I express myself more freely and somehow more precisely in a foreign language - maybe because I have been talking to myself in English ever since I was a child.</p><p>Anyways, I will try to nail down a topic or a particular event for my daily record. I swear to be as honest and unerroneous as possible, but sometimes double-checking every sentence is way too much work. To anyone reading this (which I’m assuming is NOBODY), please just bear with me ;)</p><p>And finally about today:</p><p>As we all know, I’ve been planning on studying abroad for a long time - That’s absolutely not true, ‘cuz I actually started madly planning and preparing last fall (August if my memories are correct, but wait, is memory countable??). So after sending out hundreds of application letters and cvs, I finally recieved several offers, starting March and ending depressingly yet not at all surprisingly with a rejection from ETHz. (I mean, ETHz? I should be good enough for a Phd to dream for an offer! But if I WAS good enough, then why bother?)</p><p>Have to admit that I felt so huge a sense of success and achievement when I opened a letter from A! announcing a full tuition fee waiver, that I almost immediately started dreaming about completing my degree there. Well, after some consideration (like a whole week, maybe more), I decided on TUd after all.</p><p>Alert! : None of the above contains the key point I’m making today.</p><p>The key point is that I recieved the payment letter today. Like, 4 pm.</p><p>I panicked. You see the main concern here is that, although I thought I was prepared for the cost of my 2 years abroad, I was not ready with the ‘real’ transfer of money. Or with the future prospectives, salary wise.</p><p>And here are the cold truth: I will spend 33k Euros each year (minimum) for 2 years, and IF I may get my degree on time, I recieve an income of 3500 per month before tax.</p><p>So how much after tax, you may ask?</p><p>Just 2500.</p><p>And I will spend (at least) almost 1500 on living expenses.</p><p>That will leave me living like a nearly homeless woman on the streets of Netherlands!!! I mean, not able to pay for my own house and all. And it would take me like, 5 years to pay back my parents for how much I spent during the years 2023-2025.</p><p>And another thing, if I choose to look for a job in Germany as I originally planned, I would have to 1. learn German self-taught while handling the so-called devilish courses in my programme, and 2. pay even more tax for every single Euro I earned through my occupation.</p><p>They said you need to look at the brighter side of the picture and I did, the time I can spend after work and all. But I really don’t see it as bright as before - when I still dreamed of earning a lot of money.</p><p>Then they would say that you look too far ahead, why not just stare at the road in front of you. I also did. I spent like an hour searching the internet on how to make transfer to a foreign bank. THE PAYMENT methods, the high commission charges and the exchange rate just added up to my anxieties.</p><p>Also I started to worry that, what if I can’t find anyone out there? I mean a close friend, someone I can trust and rely on in emergencies. What if I hate it out there? I mean I can get depressed because of the hedious weather. I started to understand my mom for having those panic attacks about me going abroad all on my own. Sometimes I know that things would figure themselves out as time goes by, yet still I worry.</p><p>But somehow I feel better once I’ve written these down.</p><p>There’s a, like, 3 minutes’ delay between me pushing this article to my repository and the site displaying it, so I will leave this here for a while before checking on and rereading it.</p><p>– for like a hundred times.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I guess this is it! I mean IT, my personal blog&amp;#x2F;website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was building this yesterday (constantly referring to a ste</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="Diary" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Diary/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>K-Pop Review | EXO&#39;CLOCK</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/04/10/K-Pop-Review-XOXO-Repackage/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/04/10/K-Pop-Review-XOXO-Repackage/</id>
    <published>2023-04-10T09:27:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-12T09:31:21.666Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><code>想到写这一篇其实是因为，前两天EXO11周年fm，在微博刷到了很多古早地曲；咆哮这种就抛开不讲，偶然又听到了我一直很喜欢，但如果特意去想却不会想到的歌。</code></p><p><code>歌名叫做Lucky。</code></p><p>是没有mv的一首歌，好在有几场比较高清的舞台——没有编舞的那种，只是几个人在台上走来走去，唱唱歌挥挥手。</p><p>去年年底又翻到这首歌的舞台，看了之后突然很感动，在微博打了几句话不知道怎么表达，最后进了草稿箱：</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">歌曲是能够承载记忆的：</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">粉色泛着亮光的舞台，confetti落在头发上，手比出L是lucky也是EXOL。</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">关于我们降落在同一个星球这件事。</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>今年再次看到，同样的一群人老得老胖得胖，还有韩国水光肌的加持，所有人都不太好看——至少和当年相比。</p><p>好吧，至少唱歌是有进步的。至少有些人有进步。</p><p>有进步的人还有我：虽说早年听过这首歌的中文版，但这回靠自己听懂了一部分歌词还是很让人激动的——学习有用。</p><p>나 착하게 살아서 그래</p><p>一定是因为我善良地生活，才会这样幸运！</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;想到写这一篇其实是因为，前两天EXO11周年fm，在微博刷到了很多古早地曲；咆哮这种就抛开不讲，偶然又听到了我一直很喜欢，但如果特意去想却不会想到的歌。&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;歌名叫做Lucky。&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;是没有mv的一首歌</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Review | 朱自清</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/04/10/Review-%E6%9C%B1%E8%87%AA%E6%B8%85/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/04/10/Review-%E6%9C%B1%E8%87%AA%E6%B8%85/</id>
    <published>2023-04-10T07:59:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-10T08:00:56.283Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>23-04-07 in 新清华学堂</p><p>看完之后我一个劲地说，太会跳，太会跳，太会跳。</p><p>所以有特别喜欢的几幕，首先是第一幕，学生簇拥着老师的场景，一开场群舞这样跳让人觉得生命力太饱满了。甚至看得有点想哭。</p><p>还有三个朱自清那里，有人轻轻笑了，但我觉得那里的表现力特别好。情感特别丰满。最后一幕朱自清在绸缎的波浪里跳舞也很好看。</p><p>不太喜欢的点是背影那一幕，觉得有声和无声的切换不太优雅，有点不自然。另外那一幕的配乐是歌词浑厚的一首曲子，体感很突兀…</p><p>（个人感觉是如果全剧都不要用带歌词的曲子最好了</p><p>舞美以灯光为主要的表现点，个人感觉是比较浅显的。颜色，追光，定点和全亮。每一个象征和暗示意义都很容易get，欣赏门槛并不高。贵在感情饱满，生命力丰沛，舞的力度和情感传达都非常到位。</p><p>好看！</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;23-04-07 in 新清华学堂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;看完之后我一个劲地说，太会跳，太会跳，太会跳。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所以有特别喜欢的几幕，首先是第一幕，学生簇拥着老师的场景，一开场群舞这样跳让人觉得生命力太饱满了。甚至看得有点想哭。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;还有三个朱自清那里，有人轻轻笑</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Review | 유열의 음악앨범</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/04/10/Review-%E6%9F%B3%E7%83%88%E7%9A%84%E9%9F%B3%E4%B9%90%E4%B8%93%E8%BE%91/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/04/10/Review-%E6%9F%B3%E7%83%88%E7%9A%84%E9%9F%B3%E4%B9%90%E4%B8%93%E8%BE%91/</id>
    <published>2023-04-10T06:13:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-12T09:31:05.505Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>其实是第二次看了，上一次还是刚追完鬼怪，那时候为了补足初恋组意难平看过，却没能如愿吃到一大口糖。反而看到最后都觉得怅然若失，不懂两个人为什么突然分开，又为什么突然释然。</p><p>这次看倒是觉得，啊就是这样，90年代的氛围，几年不见还是会挂念，会一直往没人看的信箱里写信——反倒是通讯技术发达了，却更联络不上了。</p><p>所以每一次重逢都像是命中注定。就像每一次分别那样。</p><p>“别跑了，好吗。会受伤的。”</p><p>最终还是在两个人事业都较为顺利稳定的时候再次见面了，好像也只有这样才能那样笑着。然后以笑回应。</p><p>其实觉得是oe来的，好像两个人会漫长地出现在彼此的生命里，好像无法割舍，好像无法迈步——但无法迈步的结果大概是“我们结婚吧”。</p><p>但下一次阻挠呢。下雨的人生应该怎么办才好呢，如果只有艳阳高照的时候才能体面相爱的话。下一次分离要怎么办呢。</p><p>“原来是这样的心情啊。”</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;其实是第二次看了，上一次还是刚追完鬼怪，那时候为了补足初恋组意难平看过，却没能如愿吃到一大口糖。反而看到最后都觉得怅然若失，不懂两个人为什么突然分开，又为什么突然释然。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这次看倒是觉得，啊就是这样，90年代的氛围，几年不见还是会挂念，会一直往没人看的信箱里写信</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="movie" scheme="http://example.com/tags/movie/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Review | The English Patient</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/04/10/Review-The-English-Patient/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/04/10/Review-The-English-Patient/</id>
    <published>2023-04-10T05:54:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-10T06:01:28.859Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>we are the real countries.</p><p>刚看完，倒着回顾一下。第一个喜欢的场景是katherine在洞里写下的留言。她写在almasy的书上，好浪漫。我容易被这种虚无缥缈的表白或者说升华感动，但细想又觉得没必要。</p><p>没有久别就没有重逢：I’ve always loved you. would it be less pain this love would seem less beautiful.</p><p>说爱太容易了，说不占有也是不负责任的一种。忘记我，又爱得发狂，不占有，又嫉妒地发疯。把一切都说成爱，把要遵守的，值得维护的都放在所谓爱情之后：其实只是疯掉了。爱不是软肋，执念才是。</p><p>almasy的请求那里，我以为护士会在颤抖着打开两瓶安瓿之后停下，哭一声说，not today。不要在今天，不知道为什么，我只是觉得他不应该在那天死掉。</p><p>我以为他会被拒绝，然后一切在静止和等待中收场：还会有下一个这样的日子，总有一天护士会答应他。</p><p>可能战争已经太压抑了。可能导演觉得如果这样结局太残忍。</p><p>其实更喜欢的是护士的爱情故事。很有意思。</p><p>爱过的人都死了，所以桥下有炸弹那个情节设计非常好。他刚跑出去的时候我甚至没有意识到护士的天生buff，看到护士惊慌失措的样子也跟着非常害怕。我觉得这一次也要应验，才是不俗的故事。但看他拆弹的样子又觉得not this time，手抖了，桥上来了坦克，但这次应该能成。</p><p>结果真的成了，这里是下一个很喜欢的场景。很流畅地衔接在拆弹后面，人们欢呼着德国投降的消息，城市在狂欢，hana和一直不待见的david跳舞。下雨了，他们抬着担架四处跑着让almasy淋雨。</p><p>好像所有的眼泪都应该在这个时候流下，所有的委屈在此刻才能倾诉。我想到david的手指，在他愤怒地控诉almasy的时候，我其实并没有太共情他。但德国投降那一天却突然感受到了汹涌的委屈和痛意。</p><p>他最终还是没有杀掉男主。</p><p>雕像上面有炸弹，非常好的设计。和前面到处都是炸弹，钢琴，路边，到处都是呼应了。</p><p>再往前就不太喜欢了。尤其是护士情绪化过头地走向好友遗物的时候。I mean for gods sake，拆弹员就在你脚底下蹲着，你自己不活了不要紧，不能trigger一个地雷把人家也炸飞吧？</p><p>最后说最后一个场景，大概是拆弹队长走的那天，两人说都会时常去那个教堂。可能会遇见的事说成总有一天，好像就变成了一定会重逢了。</p><p>然后护士笑了笑。</p><p>战争结束了，她的一生还很长，当然可以爱上好多人。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;we are the real countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;刚看完，倒着回顾一下。第一个喜欢的场景是katherine在洞里写下的留言。她写在almasy的书上，好浪漫。我容易被这种虚无缥缈的表白或者说升华感动，但细想又觉得没必要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;没有久别就没有重逢</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World!</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/04/10/hello-world/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/04/10/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2023-04-10T05:42:06.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-12T09:30:50.812Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is where I store my thoughts, reviews and life experiences.</p><p>May time always be with me.</p><p>;)</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is where I store my thoughts, reviews and life experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May time always be with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;;)&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
